<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mountain on Martin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/tags/mountain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mountain on Martin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 19:00:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mcdowell.si/tags/mountain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter warmth by croud sourcing</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2013/winter-warmth-by-croud-sourcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 19:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2013/winter-warmth-by-croud-sourcing/</guid>
      <description>One thing to note to anyone attempting to hike up the Snežnik mountain is that the place is quite remote. If you set off from Ljubljana the road takes you past Postojna and towards Croatia and you then have to drive on a gravel road for quite some time to get to the Sviščaki village. From there the route takes you through a beautiful bear country forest.
About half an hour or so from the summit I walked onto this clearing where there was a lot of chopped wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Llyn y Fan Fach</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/llyn-y-fan-fach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2010 18:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/llyn-y-fan-fach/</guid>
      <description>Today I was here. Took me a while to get here and find it. Had to give up the whole trek round the mountain ridges as I was going to run out of daylight by the end of the hike.
KPICASA_GALLERY(LlynYFanFach)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally completed the Rosebush walk</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2009/finally-completed-the-rosebush-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 19:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2009/finally-completed-the-rosebush-walk/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1106&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;rdquo;] Grim looking Pantmaenog forrest, or what is left of it[/caption]
It actually called Foel Cwmcerwyn and is the walk no. 20 in the book. There hasn&amp;rsquo;t been any proper rain for a couple of weeks so it looked promising. I had to abandon this walk weeks ago due to the fact that one big part of the walk was transformed into quite a substantial stream.
None of that this time, the sun was up, no sign of the before mentioned stream.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>