<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United Kingdom on Martin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/tags/united-kingdom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in United Kingdom on Martin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 19:59:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mcdowell.si/tags/united-kingdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Freshwater West meets Harry Potter and Robin Hood</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2009/freshwater-west-meets-harry-potter-and-robin-hood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 19:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2009/freshwater-west-meets-harry-potter-and-robin-hood/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1193&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Freshwater West beach in Pembrokeshire&amp;rdquo;]  [/caption]
Of course not literally, but it was published today in the local newspaper that the Freshwater West (the location of one of my recent trecks: The difference is in the Angle ) will be used as a filming location for the upcoming movies Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows and Ridley Scott&amp;rsquo;s Robin Hood remake.
The debate is now mostly concerning whether the beach will still be opened to the public and when the road will be closed during the filming in May and June 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The difference is in the Angle</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-difference-is-in-the-angle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2009 07:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-difference-is-in-the-angle/</guid>
      <description>I am convinced you everyone will see the huge difference in the views you see on the north side of the peninsula, compared to the south - while on the north side you see the beautiful town of Angle, but then as you move further along you are met with the view of all the petroleum and gas industries in the area with their huge piers and tall chimneys. And as you continue to the south part of the peninsula all that you can see is the vast ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackpool Mill and the Old Slebech Church</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2009/blackpool-mill-and-the-old-slebech-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2009 17:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2009/blackpool-mill-and-the-old-slebech-church/</guid>
      <description>This one the walk no 27 taken from the book and is a bit of a deviation from the books theme - it being that there are 41 circular walks in Pembrokeshire . Well this walk is still in Pembrokeshire but it is not at all circular. However the authors can be forgiven for this as it is a very nice easy walk with some nice views, especially at the main Slebech estate (see their website for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Message from John Cleese to the Citizens of the US</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/to-the-citizens-of-the-united-states-of-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/to-the-citizens-of-the-united-states-of-america/</guid>
      <description>I saw this somewhere on the internet and found it hilarious. I apologise to any US citizen if he/she is offended but this is really good!
 To The citizens of the United States of America :
In light of your failure to nominate competent candidates for President of the USA and thus to govern yourselves, we hereby give notice of the revocation of your independence, effective immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Queen to visit Slovenia</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-queen-to-visit-slovenia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2008 18:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-queen-to-visit-slovenia/</guid>
      <description>I was very surprised to hear that the British Queen Elisabeth II . is to visit Slovenia soon.
 Buckingham Palace press releases
 ANNOUNCEMENT OF STATE VISITS TO SLOVENIA AND SLOVAKIA
26 June 2008
THE FOLLOWING STATEMENT IS ISSUED BY THE PRESS SECRETARY TO THE QUEEN
The Queen and The Duke of Edinburgh will pay State Visits to: Slovenia, at the invitation of President Dr Danilo Tuerk ; and Slovakia , at the invitation of President Ivan Gasparovic , during this Autumn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydive London for a day</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I did what I wanted to do for a long while - to actually skydive in the UK. I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting it off for a long time, lately mostly due to the weather we have been having. Last weekend the weather was OK, no flu lingering in the background and no lameness in any of the legs :-) The Skydive London dropzone is situated about 3 hours drive away from Haverfordwest , adjacent to the town of Swindon .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
