<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motorcycling on Martin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/tags/motorcycling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Motorcycling on Martin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mcdowell.si/tags/motorcycling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bike trip to Slovenia 2022</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2022/bike-trip-to-slovenia-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2022/bike-trip-to-slovenia-2022/</guid>
      <description>Herefordshire to Slovenia UK to Slovenia, Day 1 of 2
Had a similar plan to last year&amp;rsquo;s bike trip but this time consolidates both ways into 2 day riding each way.
My first worry was what was going to happen in Folkestone. Not two weeks before there were severe delays in the area and drivers were queuing for hours on end to get to the Eurotunnel port.
Thankfully they seemed to have sorted out the issues and there was only a slight delay at passport control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike trip to Slovenia 2021</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2021/bike-trip-to-slovenia-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2021/bike-trip-to-slovenia-2021/</guid>
      <description>Had been to Slovenia many many times since I moved to the UK aback in 2007 but mostly flying and mostly with easyJet. Drove here and back once in those years and that was only to do the inital move and then drive the car back as it was a Slovenian reg and a LH drive which didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense plus made the insurance a bit tricky.
Due to all the COVID issues I decided to try my first biking trip to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The KTM beast</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2020/the-ktm-beast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2020/the-ktm-beast/</guid>
      <description>My KTM in Wales in May 2021 - Click to enlarge
I finally decided to replace my Honda NC750x DCT. The Honda was a great bike, very easy to use, never stalled due to its DCT gearbox but it was very underpowered. It was a bit of a job trying to keep up with my fellow IAM riders out on our Sunday rides. Plus it didn&amp;rsquo;t help seeing this video from Yammie Noob about the top 7 dorkiest bikes .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
