<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linkedin on Martin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/tags/linkedin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linkedin on Martin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 19:06:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mcdowell.si/tags/linkedin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Filming Snow White and the Huntsman at Marloes Sands</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2011/filming-snow-white-and-the-huntsman-at-marloes-sands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 19:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2011/filming-snow-white-and-the-huntsman-at-marloes-sands/</guid>
      <description>After seeing the filming of Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows and Robin Hood on the Freshwater West beach, Third Star in Barafundle Bay we have again the film crews back in Pembrokeshire for the filming of Snow White and the Huntsman on my favourite beach Marloes Sands .
Filming should be around September 26th - 29th and should mainly involve filming of about 80 horses galloping towards a computer generated castle* on Gateholm island .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragična zgodba Tommya Jonesa</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/tragicna-zgodba-tommya-jonesa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 19:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/tragicna-zgodba-tommya-jonesa/</guid>
      <description>Gospa Hamer, žena vrtnarja v majhni južno-valežanski vasici, naj bi ponoči sanjala o dečku, ki se je izgubil slab mesec poprej. Ko se je le opogumila in prepričala moža, da ji pomaga, se je 2. septembra leta 1900 skupaj z nekaj sorodniki odpravila na lastno iskalno akcijo. Ko je skupina z gospo Hamer na čelu prispela do grebena nad jezerom Cwm llwch, okoli pol kilometra zahodno od vrha gore Pen-y-fan, je gospa Hammer naenkrat zakričala od groze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blejski vintgar, Pokljuka, Pohorje and other Slovenian gems</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/blejski-vintgar-pokljuka-pohorje-and-other-slovenian-gems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 12:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/blejski-vintgar-pokljuka-pohorje-and-other-slovenian-gems/</guid>
      <description>These were some of the photos from my latest trip to Slovenia.
KPICASA_GALLERY(KopeInHudaLuknja,BlejskiVintgar,OstrovicaHochosterwitz,GospaSvetaMariaSaal)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing the eminence, and then some</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/climbing-the-eminence-and-then-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 19:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/climbing-the-eminence-and-then-some/</guid>
      <description>My original plan for this days hike was Y-Garn but that soon changed once I reached the peak and gazed upon the inviting summits of Glyder Fawr and Glyder Fach. As if that was not enough and after all the struggle of descending off Glyder Fach I made a silly move and ascended up Tryfan. Now for those who haven&amp;rsquo;t been up this mountain I must tell you it more resembles a high stack of very big rocks that in many cases precariously lean on each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cwm Gwesyn and the Llyn Brianne reservoir</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/cwm-gwsyn-and-the-llyn-brianne-reservoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/cwm-gwsyn-and-the-llyn-brianne-reservoir/</guid>
      <description>This is marked as the toughest walk in the Brecon Becons &amp;amp; South Wales book and it turned out to be living up to its name. The most difficult part was trying to not get lost on Bryn Rhudd at the same time as not loosing interest in the walk as well. The views on there are almost desert-like, nothing but dried grass and boggy moors. Even the sheep are sensible enough not to stray that far from the valleys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wales prepovedal elektronske ovratnike za pse in mačke</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/wales-prepovedal-elektronske-ovratnike-za-pse-in-macke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 13:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/wales-prepovedal-elektronske-ovratnike-za-pse-in-macke/</guid>
      <description>V sredo, 24. marca 2010 je v Walesu v veljavo stopil pravilnik Valežanske Skupščinske Vlade (Welsh Assembly Government) , ki prepoveduje uporabo elektronskih (električnih) ovratnikov pri psih in mačkah.
Ti ovratniki se v večini primerov uporabljajo za odpravljanje neželenih vedenjskih navad pri psih. V skupščinski debati so utemeljili pravilnik s tem, da so ti ovratniki nepotrebno mučenje živali in pogosto ostanejo orodje lenih in brezbrižnih lastnikov, ki ne znajo odpravljati neželenih navad pri svojih hišnih ljubljencih na noben drug način.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elan valley, Snowdonia and the longest place name in Europe</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/elan-valley-snowdonia-and-the-longest-place-name-in-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 22:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/elan-valley-snowdonia-and-the-longest-place-name-in-europe/</guid>
      <description>Here are just some of the best photos from the trip.
KPICASA_GALLERY(WalesMidAndNorth2010)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woody Pines in Cardigan</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/woody-pines-in-cardigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 18:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/woody-pines-in-cardigan/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1566&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;rdquo;] Woody Pines (woodypines.com)[/caption]
What a great night. Never though I would like country &amp;amp; western music. Funny thing to hear it in the heart of Wales.
The guys played great and made a great atmosphere despite the hall not being completely full.
As a fellow guitarist I was impressed and did appreciate how quickly the vocalist and guitarist Woody recovered from a broken guitar string.
By the way, I thought the name of the band &amp;ldquo;Woody Pines&amp;rdquo; came from an association with the local North Carolina forests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dara Ó Briain in Bristol on 2 March 2010</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/dara-o-briain-in-bristol-on-2-march-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 20:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/dara-o-briain-in-bristol-on-2-march-2010/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1552&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;221&amp;rdquo;] Photo: The Sun[/caption]
This was the first time I have gone to a headlining stand-up comedy show. The one in the comedy store in London was similar in ways very very different. This was in a proper theatre and there was no intimidation or any kind of boo-ing coming from the crowd. In fact there was a fare bit of very well humoured picking of certain members of the crowd from Dara&amp;rsquo;s side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Llyn y Fan Fach</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/llyn-y-fan-fach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2010 18:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/llyn-y-fan-fach/</guid>
      <description> Today I was here. Took me a while to get here and find it. Had to give up the whole trek round the mountain ridges as I was going to run out of daylight by the end of the hike.
KPICASA_GALLERY(LlynYFanFach)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stranded sheep in the Blue Lagoon</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/stranded-sheep-in-the-blue-lagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 21:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2010/stranded-sheep-in-the-blue-lagoon/</guid>
      <description>The Sunday between Christmas and the New Year I spent hiking around Pembrokeshire and this time I went for walk no. 12 (Around Ynys Barry) taken from the book mentioned in some of my previous posts There is a local attraction called the Blue Lagoon that is just a few minutes away from the Aber Eiddy (also known as Abereiddy) car park where the walk originates from. The lagoon is actually an old man-made slate mining pit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>