<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>skydiving on Martin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/categories/skydiving/</link>
    <description>Recent content in skydiving on Martin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 21:14:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mcdowell.si/categories/skydiving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ooops, or how I ripped my container on a Cessna 206, part 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 21:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206-2/</guid>
      <description>I have now managed to send off the container to the manufacturer Aerodyne in Florida . I have just driven back from Swansea where I send off the container through a DHL ServicePoint location in the Parc Tawe Staples shop. Great service, if you ask me, as you don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay a high price to have your packed shipped and you also choose what boy its going to be sent in - the price of shipment depends on the size of the box, but with a upper weight limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ooops, or how I ripped my container on a Cessna 206, part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 19:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206/</guid>
      <description>My recent visit to the motherland gave me the opportunity for yet another skydiving session, I joined my instructor and mentor Aleš Debeljak from the Paranoia skydiving school.
All went well and on the third jump of the second day just as I exited the Cessna 206 I apparently managed to hook my rig on the side of the door which resulted in a nasty tear in my container on the reserve parachute flap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6 in Deland - a great day for jumping</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-6-in-deland-a-great-day-for-jumping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 02:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-6-in-deland-a-great-day-for-jumping/</guid>
      <description>The morning was a bit foggy but that soon cleared and the weather hold on the jumps was lifted by about 11am. Then we went full throttle as we knwe we might have another weather related bad jump day tomorrow. I managed to make a record 8 jumps, the last one being the sunset jump. Usually they are at a higher altitude but this one was the same as the others, nevertheless it was completely full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5 in Deland - back in the air again</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-5-in-deland-back-in-the-air-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-5-in-deland-back-in-the-air-again/</guid>
      <description>The morning had low clouds but we hoped that they would soon lift and that we would see blue skies again - unfortunately this took much longer than first predicted as we started jumping at about 1PM.
As it was a Sunday most of the skydivers wanted to make the most of the day and the DZ became very busy as there were 3 planes flying at any given time (Twin Otter, PAC 820, Skyvan or Porter), today we saw the first appearance of the Skyvan .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydive Sebastian</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/skydive-sebastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/skydive-sebastian/</guid>
      <description>As we woke this morning we could only take a depressing glance out of the window and despair over the rubbish weather we had. It was bucketing down. We had to decide either to stay in the house, go on a (inside) sightseeing tour, or drive to a DZ that does not have bad weather. We chose on the latter and decided to go to Skydive Sebastian - a DZ located in the Florida town called Sebastian (duh) just over 2 hours drive from Deland, passing Titusville and Cape Canaveral on the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 in Deland</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-4-in-deland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 02:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-4-in-deland/</guid>
      <description>The weather, again, was a bit of a disappointment. In the morning we were not sure if we should bother even going to the DZ. Our landlord Dennis said that the clouds should break up. When we came there the DZ was closed for jumps and it looked like nobody was going to jump today.
However later in the afternoon the clouds cleared and I managed to do 2 jumps, the winds were quite strong and sometimes unpredictable, but I was quite pleased with my landings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 in Deland (really spent in Daytona Beach)</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-3-in-deland-really-spent-in-daytona-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 01:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-3-in-deland-really-spent-in-daytona-beach/</guid>
      <description>As the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t very promising most of us managed to do only two jumps, the last one in many cases being in the rain and believe me, it is not nice or romantic to free fly through rain. It feels like you are being pricked with pins all over your face. I did a couple of three-way jump with Miha and Barbara and I think it went well considering our experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 at Deland</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-2-at-deland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 02:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-2-at-deland/</guid>
      <description>Now that I have got my reserve deployment out of the way I can get to some good and proper skydiving. Managed to get the record number of jumps for a day - 5 and I could have done at least one more but I had to arrange another rental car for our group.
The picture on the left is showing our makeshift hangar - the flag has now been moved to a proper flag post close to the boarding zone - pics to follow :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first parachute reserve</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/my-first-parachute-reserve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2008 04:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/my-first-parachute-reserve/</guid>
      <description>Not only was it my first jump at Deland or in the U.S. in general, but it also ended up being the jump that I had to deploy my reserve. The jump started well as a 5-way group with the local instructor Carl. We broke off the formation at 1.500 m and opened at approx. 1.200 - 1.000 m. The parachute opened a bit slower than usual but I very quickly realized something was very wrong, the canopy was making me go in circles, but not spirals, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t loosing height quickly but it all came down to my first cell from the left (the parachute is a 7-cell Atair Dragon 170).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 in Orlando</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-4-in-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 12:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-4-in-orlando/</guid>
      <description>Feeling better after the midnights tunnel session, still having problems with some of the techniques but my instructor Aljaž says there are visible improvements. I hope so as I sometimes feel like a sack of potatoes in a tornado when I&amp;rsquo;m in the tunnel.
Today marks the end of the tunnel sessions for most of us as our group will be moving out of the hotel and heading up to Deland, FL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 in Orlando</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-3-in-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-3-in-orlando/</guid>
      <description>This is getting to be really tough. Last nights session started at midnight and I somewhat remember going to bed at 2am. This morning there are another three sessions, the first one on which starts at 9am. I am well and truly sore all over and hadn&amp;rsquo;t had this much physical exercise in a good few years.
Most of us, who are doing RW work in the tunnel don&amp;rsquo;t have much time to do anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first Saturday in Orlando</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-first-saturday-in-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-first-saturday-in-orlando/</guid>
      <description>No real time to do anything else here as most of the time is spent either briefing for the tunnel, debriefing for the tunnel or actually IN the tunnel. I have hardly any time to eat - in fact I have only eaten once - yesterday&amp;rsquo;s breakfast - and that is it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day in Orlando</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/first-day-in-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 05:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/first-day-in-orlando/</guid>
      <description>The wind tunnel training started a day before I expected so I had to get up at about 6am. I did 5x2 minutes in the morning, then another 5x2 minutes in the afternoon and I have just completed another 2x2 minutes session. I have now finished debriefing and it is ten minutes to one in the morning! By my home watch it is just before 6am!
  Don&amp;rsquo;t even think that flying in a wind tunnel is easy and not exhausting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First leg to Florida: Hickstead</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/first-leg-to-florida-hickstead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 20:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/first-leg-to-florida-hickstead/</guid>
      <description>Here I am, in lovely Hickstead, somewhere between Crawley (Gatwick airport) and Brighton in the local Travelodge. Took me about four and a half hours to get here from Haverfordwest and I can sincerely say, I am nackered. The drive was very smooth although I knew I was going to be hitting the London&amp;rsquo;s circular road (the M25) at rush hour. My satnav took me from the M4 via a shortcut to the M3 and then on the M25.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A great tragedy</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/a-great-tragedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/a-great-tragedy/</guid>
      <description>As usual some of the media outlets are taking a completely wrong ignorant spin on this genuine and sad tragedy.
Slovenia lost a great pilot Viktor Bečan (a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;Som&amp;rdquo;). My sincere condolences go to his family. My hopes for a quick recovery go to the surviving co-pilot Savo Medved
Photo on left featuring the &amp;ldquo;Som&amp;rdquo; made by Lubi in Novo mesto (Prečna) in June 2007.
Slovenia lost a legend among skydiving planes the &amp;ldquo;Fata&amp;rdquo; - Antonov 2 from the Paranoia Skydiving school (part of the ŠOLT organization) that fulfilled the dreams of many skydivers in becoming the vessel for them to do their first skydive jumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP Fata and Som</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/rip-fata-and-som/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2008 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2008/rip-fata-and-som/</guid>
      <description>I must sadly inform you that the Antonov-2 airplane (we lovingly called &amp;ldquo;Fata&amp;rdquo;) from which I learned how to skydive and did many jumps, the most recent ones in September 2007, crashed in the mountains near Trbovlje at about 1pm local time.
  Photo taken by Daniel Zavratnik in Bovec in August 2007. Viktor Bečan a.k.a. &amp;#39;Som&amp;#39; is the chap on the left in a green t-shirt. In the middle is one of our lovely fellow skydivers and on the right is the legend of Slovene skydiving who runs, in my opinion, the best skydiving school in Slovenia - Aleš Debeljak a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydive London for a day</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I did what I wanted to do for a long while - to actually skydive in the UK. I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting it off for a long time, lately mostly due to the weather we have been having. Last weekend the weather was OK, no flu lingering in the background and no lameness in any of the legs :-) The Skydive London dropzone is situated about 3 hours drive away from Haverfordwest , adjacent to the town of Swindon .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return to skydiving</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2007/return-to-skydiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2007/return-to-skydiving/</guid>
      <description>After a one year sebaticle I finally got the chance to do some skydiving again. The best thing about it, besides, of course, skydiving, was that I could do it at my old home drop zone Prečna in Novo mesto in the southern part of Slovenia. The other good part was that I could jump from the old Antonov 2 (the one we use bares the nickname &amp;ldquo;Fata&amp;rdquo;. I did my first student jumps from it two years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bodyflight Bedford indoor skydiving [or how to fly around a room and not having a hangover the next day]</title>
      <link>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2007/bodyflight-bedford-indoor-skydiving-or-how-to-fly-around-a-room-and-not-having-a-hangover-the-next-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mcdowell.si/post/2007/bodyflight-bedford-indoor-skydiving-or-how-to-fly-around-a-room-and-not-having-a-hangover-the-next-day/</guid>
      <description>It was a great day probably more suitable for outdoor skydiving than indoor skydiving. I set of from home early Saturday morning and arrived at Bedford five and a half hours later after stupidly ignoring my satnav and adding another hour to my already long journey. The Bodyflight facility is situated in a generally abandoned ex-military complex outside of Bedford near the A6. I heard it was used to do tests for the Concorde.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
